Guide to the Harold L. Creal papers, [ca. 1916]-1986
Creal, Harold L. papers, [ca. 1916]-1986
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Harold L. Creal papers, [ca. 1916]-1986.
4326
Harold L. Creal, 1896-1987.
2 cubic ft.
Correspondence, notes, speeches, memoranda, certificates, clippings, financial records, photographs, and printed material.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, notes, speeches, memoranda, certificates, clippings, financial records, photographs, and printed material concerning the American Agriculturist, Inc.; Century Farms in various New York counties; GLF and the New York State Grange; the New York State Council of Farmer Cooperatives, Inc.; the New York State Fair; and the New York Farm Bureau. Personal papers include materials pertaining to the Cornell University Alumni Association, YMCA, church work, and the Homer, New York, school and Planning Board.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Harold Leroy Creal graduated from Cornell University in 1921. He operated a dairy farm in Cortland County, New York. From 1932 to 1938, he served as Supervisor of the Town of Homer, New York. He also served in the New York State Assembly from 1939 to 1950, as Director of the New York State Fair from 1950 to 1955, as Director of the Dairymen's League Cooperative Association, and as Director of the Cooperative Grange League Federation.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, notes, speeches, memoranda, certificates, clippings, financial records, photographs, and printed material concerning the American Agriculturist, Inc.; Century Farms in various New York counties; GLF and the New York State Grange; the New York State Council of Farmer Cooperatives, Inc.; the New York State Fair; and the New York Farm Bureau. Personal papers include materials pertaining to the Cornell University Alumni Association, YMCA, church work, and the Homer, New York, school and Planning Board.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Creal, Harold L., 1896-1987.; American Agriculturist, Inc.; Cornell University Alumni Association.; Homer (N.Y.).Planning Board.; National Grange.; New York State Council of Farmer Cooperatives.; New York State Fair.; New York State Farm Bureau Federation.; New York State Grange.
Subjects:
Agricultural exhibitions--New York (State); Agriculture--New York (State); Agriculture, Cooperative--New York (State); Young Men's Christian associations.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIAL
Harold L. Creal. Oral History. Ithaca, N.Y.: New York State College of Agriculture and Life Sciences Historical Documentation Program.
CONTAINER LIST
- Accounts for Building House, 1956, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Accounts for Building House on Hudson Street, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Agway - Board of Directors Meetings, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Alpha Gamma Rho, 1942-1978 (Box 1, Folder 4-5)
- Alumni Association Outstanding Alumni, 1981-1986 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Alumni Association, 1980-1986 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- American Agriculturist, Inc., 1976-1979, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Artificial Breeders' Cooperative, Inc., 1949-1955 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- H.E. Babcock, 1921, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Century Farms, 1969-1981 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Chenango County, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Century Farm - Madison County, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Century Farm - Onondaga County, 1977-1980 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Century Farm - Schuyler County, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Century Farm - Seneca County, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Century Farm - Bill Worth, 1974-1980 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- College of Agriculture, 1977-1981 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Congregational Church, 1973-1984 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Farm Bureau, 1976-1982 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Cortland County Republican Committee, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 21-22)
- Council of Churches, Capital Funds, 1961-1966 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Council of Churches, Finance Committee, 1962-1980 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Farmers and World Affairs, 1964-1969 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Financial Records, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- John B. Folmer - Creal Tax Papers, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- G.L.F., 1955 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- State Grange - Committee on Education, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Empire State Grange, 1966-1976 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Home Farm Problem, 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Homer Centralized School, 1947-1978 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Homer GLF Service, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Town of Homer - Planning Board, 1958-1971 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Men's Garden Clubs, 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Milk - Herrell DeGraff, 1951-1954 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Correspondence - Thomas E. Milliman, 1950-1970 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Miscellaneous Accounts, etc., 1927-1953 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Miscellaneous Accounts, etc. (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Miscellany (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Miscellaneous Notes and Speeches (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Miscellaneous - Commission on Agriculture, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Muscial Museum, State Fair, 1966-1978 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Dean W.I. Myers, 1948-1950, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Old Bull Proofs, 1936, 1944-1945 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- New York Farm Bureau, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- New York State Council of Churches, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- New York State Council of Farmer Cooperatives, Inc., 1954-1958 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- New York State Council of Farmer Cooperatives, Inc., 1956-1960 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- New York State Council of Farmer Cooperatives, Inc., 1954-1962 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- New York State Rural Safety Council, 1955-1985 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Old Times, 1930-1964 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Personal Items, 1964-1971 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Christmas Letters, Personal, Miscellaneous, 1956-1979 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Personal Items, 1961-1974 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Personal - Bill of Sale, Cattle, Equipment, Supplies, Rental Contract to Leonard B. Morgan, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Personal - Certificates (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Personal - "The Speed Demon" (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Personal Letters and Clippings, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Personal Items (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Photographs (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Photograph: G.L.F. Dinner for Directors and Staff, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- New York State Fair, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Repair to Ahrens House, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Republican County Committee, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Creal Retirement Dinner, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Rotary Education, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Rural Church Institute, 1956-1958 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Rural Citizens for Good Government, 1950-1962 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Salvation Army, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Soil Conservation, 1950-1957 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Tompkins County Wage Dispute, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Tours, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Tuberculosis Testing, 1930-1965 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- United Fund, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- United Fund - Rural Advance Gifts, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Witter Agricultural Museum, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- YMCA, 1967-1981 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- YMCA, 1976-1986 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Zoning - Town of Homer, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Century Farms (Box 2, Folder 40-41)
- Notes, Memos, etc. (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Notes and Speeches (Box 2, Folder 43-44)